Howard Norton Cook Papers
Howard Norton Cook Papers
1866-1979
Cook, Howard Norton, 1901-1980
12.5 linear ft.
Correspondence (1928-1972); artwork (original watercolors and reproductions); writings by Cook (articles, essays, reminiscences about the Taos community, statements and notes on Cook's artistic philosophy); and memorabilia, including financial and legal documents, and printed material (articles, reviews, clippings about Cook, exhibition announcements, invitations, and catalogs). Correspondents include artists Ernest L. Blumenschein, Victor Candell, Jean Charlot, Fred Conway, Russell Cowles, Andrew Dasburg, Lamar Dodd, Ernest Fiene, Lez Haas, John Haley, Ward Lockwood, Henry Lee McFee, B.J.O. Nordfeldt, Arthur Osver, Rudolph Ruzicka, Millard Sheets, and Carl Zigrosser. Other correspondents include Margaret Anderson, Joseph Blumenthal, John Hodgdon Bradley, J. Frank Dobie, and Lenore Marshall. Extensive correspondence relating to Cook's mural work includes that of the Mayo Clinic, the U. S. Post Office, the U.S. Public Buildings Administration, and the U.S. Treasury Department.
148901
Biographical History
American painter, illustrator, muralist.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1866 to 1972, the Howard Norton Cook Papers comprises correspondence, artwork, writings, and memorabilia of the American illustrator, muralist, and painter (1901-1980). The collection not only illuminates the personal life and professional career of the artist, but also reflects the multiculturalism of the the Southwest and the growth of the Taos art community.
The Correspondence-subject Files (Boxes 1-9) encompasses family and general correspondence, including both incoming business and personal letters and a number of outgoing holograph drafts, as well as photographs, reports, and printed material. Spanning 1928 through the 1960s, letters between Howard Cook and his wife, artist Barbara Latham, together with a small amount of printed material (artwork reproductions and exhibition catalogs) relating to her career, constitute the bulk of the family material. The remainder of the Correspondence Subject Files comprises letters of artists (Ernest L. Blumenschein, Victor Candell, Jean Charlot, Frederick Conway, Russell Cowles, Andrew Dasburg, Lamar Dodd, Ernest Fiene, Lez Haas, John Haley, Ward Lockwood, Henry Lee McFee, B. J. O. Nordfeldt, Arthur Osver, Rudolph Ruzicka, Millard Sheets, Carl Zigrosser); academic institutions (Dartmouth College, San Jose State College, University of Hawaii, University of Illinois, University of Texas, Washington University); and agents and private galleries (Raymond Burr Galleries, Grand Central Art Galleries, Grand Central Moderns, Frank K. M. Rehn, Rosequist Galleries, E. Weyhe). Correspondence also includes that with art institutions and museums (Art Association of Newport, Art Institute of Chicago, Associated American Artists, Baltimore Museum of Art, Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Museum of Modern Art, Museum of New Mexico, Philbrook Art Center); authors (Margaret Anderson of Common Ground, John Hodgdon Bradley, J. Frank Dobie, Lenore Marshall); clients and patrons (Joseph Blumenthal of Spiral Press, Mayo Clinic, R. Gray Winnan, Woodcut Society); and professional organizations (American Artists Group, American Institute of Graphic Arts, Artists Equity Association, Associated American Artists, Society of American Graphic Artists). Materials relating to the production of Cook's mural paintings for the post office in Pittsburgh and the courthouse and post office in San Antonio (U. S. Post Office, U. S. Public Buildings Administration, U. S. Treasury Department) demonstrate federal support for the arts during the Depression through the early 1940s. Additional documentation concerning the relationship between the arts and government may be found among the material relating to the U. S. Office for Emergency Management and the U. S. Office of Civilian Defense.
Original sketches, watercolor drawings, woodcut and lithographic proofs as well as reproductions of Cook's graphic work and paintings constitute Artwork (Box 10). Original work includes drawings for an unpublished Book of the Month Club edition of Jack London's The Call of the Wild; drawings and page proofs for Cook's children's book, Sammi's Army; watercolor drawings for The Reader's Digest; a self portrait sketch; and a number of sketches for Cook's San Antonio frescoes. Reproductions include periodical illustrations arranged by title of publication in which they appeared; a portfolio of murals at the Mayo Clinic, for which Cook contributed "Man's Responsibility to Others;" and miscellaneous graphic work and paintings arranged by title.
Comprised of published and unpublished material, Cook's Writings (Box 11) are arranged alphabetically by format. They include articles, a draft essay on artist Ernest L. Blumenschein, inventories of Cook's work (some with prices), reminiscences about Taos, the transcript of a speech delivered at a retrospective exhibition of Andrew Dasburg's work, statements and notes on Cook's artistic philosophy, and miscellaneous notes, including those for the Mayo Clinic mural project.
Financial and legal material, identification and membership cards, photographs, and printed material compose Memorabilia (Boxes 12-19). Printed material includes articles, reviews, and clippings about Cook (1923-1965), exhibition announcements, invitations, and catalogs (1920s-1969) for Cook's group and one man shows, and miscellaneous periodical issues and reports. Arranged by institution, there are also a number of catalogs which Cook collected for exhibitions in which he did not participate.
Other Formats Available
Part of this collection is also available on microfilm.
Related Material
See also the
Aaron Bohrod Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Art -- Illustrators; Anderson, Margaret C.; Blumenschein, E. L. (Ernest Leonard), 1874-1960.; Blumenthal, Joseph, 1897-1990.; Bradley, John Hodgdon, 1898-; Candell, Victor.; Charlot, Jean, 1898-1979.; Conway, Fred.; Cook, Howard Norton, 1901-1980.; Cowles, Russell, 1887-; Dasburg, Andrew, 1887-1979.; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964.; Dodd, Lamar.; Fiene, Ernest, 1894-1966.; Haas, Lez.; Haley, John.; Latham, Barbara, 1896-1989.; Lockwood, Ward.; Marshall, Lenore, 1897-1971.; McFee, Henry Lee, 1886-1953.; Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson, 1878-1955.; Osver, Arthur, 1912-; Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1883-1978.; Sheets, Millard, 1907-1989.; Zigrosser, Carl, 1891-1975.; Mayo Clinic.; United States -- Post Office Department.; United States -- Public Building Administration.; United States -- Department of the Treasury.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Art and state -- United States.; Artist colonies -- New Mexico -- Taos.; Federal aid to the arts -- United States.; Illustrators -- United States.; Mural painting and decoration -- United States -- 20th century.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- Southwestern States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Announcements.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Exhibition catalogs.; Illustrations.; Invitations.; Photographs.; Sketches.; Artists.; Illustrators.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Howard Cook, 1964-1972. Kurtz letters gift of the Petrie Institute of Western American Art, 2009.
Inventory
- Family Correspondence Subject Files
  - Cook, Barbara Latham (wife)
    - 1928-1950s, 14 folders (Box 1)
    - 1960s, undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Printed material (Box 2)
  - Cook, F. Raymond (brother) and family, 1916; 1921,; undated (Box 2)
  - Cook, Frank and "Mother" (parents), 1920; 1921,; 1939,; undated (Box 2)
  - Dewar, Loretta Cook (sister) and family, 1920-1972; undated (Box 2)
  - Norton grandparents, 1866; undated correspondence; memorabilia (Box 2)
  - Perry, Marian and James (cousins), 1964-1971; undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous relatives (Box 2)
- Correspondence Subject Files
  - A (Box 3)
  - Abbott, Gordon C., 1941-1942 (Box 3)
  - Adams, Kenneth M. and Hilda, 1939-1963 (Box 3)
  - Adler, Elmer, 1941-1950 (Box 3)
  - Adler, Samuel, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art, 1952-1958 (Box 3)
  - Albright Art Gallery (Buffalo, N.Y.), 1952-1957 (Box 3)
  - Allen, James E., 1945 (Box 3)
  - Allidi, Peter, 1945 (Box 3)
  - American Artists Group, 1937-1945 (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1944; 1947 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Donald B. and Patricia, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Margaret, See Common Ground.
  - Arms, John Taylor, 1941-1953; undated (Box 3)
  - Art Association of Newport, 1953-1958 (Box 3)
  - Art Center in La Jolla, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1937-1956 (Box 3)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1951-1955; undated (Box 3)
  - Associated American Artists, 1939-1949; undated (Box 3)
  - Atlanta Art Association, See Atlanta Art Institute.
  - Atlanta Art Institute, 1950-1953 (Box 3)
  - Audubon Artists, 1945-1946; printed material (Box 3)
  - B (Box 3)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
  - Berninghaus, Oscar E. and Winifred, See Taos Arts Association.
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1952-1954 (Box 3)
  - Blake, Nancy J., 1969-1970; undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Bloch, E. Maurice, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Blumenschein, Ernest L., 1948-1952 (Box 3)
  - Blumenthal, Joseph, 1952-1972; undated (Box 3)
  - Book of the Month Club, 1945-1949 (Box 3)
    See also Artwork: Original: Drawings: Watercolors.
  - Boston Public Library, 1951-1956 (Box 3)
  - Bradley, John Hodgdon and Katharine, 1947-1958 (Box 3)
  - Breeskin, Adelyn D., See Baltimore Museum of Art.
  - Brooklyn Museum, undated (Box 3)
  - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery (Memphis, Tenn.), 1952 (Box 3)
  - Browne, Byron, 1955 (Box 3)
  - [W. S.] Budworth & Sons, 1940-1953 (Box 3)
  - [Raymond] Burr Galleries (Beverly Hills, Calif.), 1962-1964 (Box 3)
  - Butler Art Institute (Youngstown, Ohio), 1952-1953 (Box 3)
  - Bywaters, Jerry, See Dallas Museum of Fine Arts.
  - C (Box 4)
  - Calfee, William H., 1952 (Box 4)
  - California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1947; 1957 (Box 4)
  - California School of Fine Arts, 1952 (Box 4)
  - California Water Color Society, 1941; 1944 (Box 4)
  - Canade, Laura, See E. Weyhe.
  - Candell, Victor, 1951; undated (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1941-1953 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1948-1958 (Box 4)
  - Chappell, Warren, See Book of the Month Club.
  - Charlot, Jean, 1948-1956 (Box 4)
  - Chavez, Edward A., 1956; 1960,; 1964 (Box 4)
  - City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1952-1962 (Box 4)
  - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1941-1963 (Box 4)
  - Columbia Museum of Art (Columbia, S.C.), 1953 (Box 4)
  - Common Ground, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Conway, Frederick, undated (Box 4)
  - Couse, William Percy and Elizabeth, 1942-1972 (Box 4)
  - Cowie Galleries (Los Angeles, Calif.), 1948-1950 (Box 4)
  - Cowles, Russell, 1946-1951 (Box 4)
  - Craft, John Richard, See Columbia Museum of Art.
  - [El] Crepusculo, 1952-1959; undated (Box 4)
  - Cudworth, James R., 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Currier Gallery of Art (Manchester, N.H.), 1941; 1953 (Box 4)
  - D (Box 4)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1940-1960 (Box 4)
  - Dallas Print Society, 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - Dartmouth College, 1952-1958 (Box 4)
  - Dasburg, Andrew, 1955-1971 (Box 4)
  - Deines, E. Hubert, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Denver Art Museum, 1947-1960 (Box 4)
  - De Schulthess, Amalia M., 1956-1970 (Box 4)
  - Des Moines Art Center, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Devree, Howard, undated (Box 4)
  - [M. H.] De Young Memorial Museum (San Francisco), 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Dike, Phil, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Dobie, J. Frank, 1934-1964 (Box 4)
  - Dodd, Lamar and Mary, 1950-1970 (Box 4)
  - Dows, Olin, 1941; undated (Box 4)
    See also United States. Office of Civilian Defense.
  - E (Box 4)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz, 1953-1955 (Box 4)
  - Ellerbe and Company, 1951-1955 (Box 4)
    See also Mayo Clinic.
  - F (Box 4)
  - Fiene, Ernest, 1950-1957 (Box 4)
  - Fine Arts Gallery of San Diego, 1941; 1952 (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Reginald, See Museum of New Mexico.
  - [La] Fonda Art Gallery, See Karavas, Saki.
  - Ford Foundation, 1958-1960 (Box 4)
  - Fort Worth Art Association, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
  - Fowler, Alfred, See Woodcut Society.
  - G (Box 4)
  - Gamble, Edwin F., undated (Box 4)
  - Georgia Museum of Art, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Gonzalez, Xavier, 1952; undated (Box 4)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries (New York, N.Y.), 1950-1968; undated (Box 5)
    See also Grand Central Moderns (New York, N.Y.).
  - Grand Central Art Galleries Yearbooks, 1952; 1953,; 1955,; 1957,; 1958-1963; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Grand Central Moderns (New York, N.Y.), 1950-1964; undated; 6 folders (Box 5)
    See also Grand Central Art Galleries (New York, N.Y.).
  - [John Simon] Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1931-1961 (Box 5)
  - Gundlach, Waldo L., 1954-1956; undated (Box 5)
  - H (Box 5)
  - Haas, Lez, 1950; 1965,; undated (Box 5)
  - Haley, John and Monica, 1948-1959 (Box 5)
  - Hallmark Art Award, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
  - Heintzelman, Arthur W., See Boston Public Library.
  - High Museum School of Art, See Atlanta Art Institute.
  - Hogan, James Denton, See University of Illinois.
  - Horgan, Paul, 1942 (Box 5)
  - Hougland, Willard and Georgine, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  - Hubbard, Bess, undated (Box 5)
  - I (Box 6)
  - J (Box 6)
  - James, William, See Museum of Fine Arts (Boston).
  - Johnson, J. Theodore and Bobbie, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Jonson, Raymond, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Joslyn Memorial Art Museum (Omaha, Neb.), 1952 (Box 6)
  - K (Box 6)
  - Kansas State Federation of Art, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Karavas, Saki, 1953-1971 (Box 6)
  - Kennedy & Company, 1944-1952; undated (Box 6)
  - Kent, Norman, 1945 (Box 6)
  - [M.] Knoedler & Co., Inc., 1944; 1946 (Box 6)
  - Korn, Ann and Karl, 1955; undated (Box 6)
  - Kozuszek, Larry and Jane, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo and Sara, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Kurtz, William C. and Alma, 1964-1979 (Box 6)
  - L (Box 6)
  - Library of Congress, 1946-1952 (Box 6)
  - Lockwood, Ward, 1940-1959 (Box 6)
  - Luyber, Joseph, 1950 (Box 6)
  - M (Box 6)
  - McFee, Henry Lee and Eleanor, 1950-1953; undated (Box 6)
  - Marshall, Lenore G., 1955-1964 (Box 6)
  - Mayo Clinic, 1952-1955 (Box 6)
    See also Ellerbe and Company; Artwork: Reproductions: Murals at Mayo Clinic.
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.), 1941; 1950-1953 (Box 6)
  - Miller, George C., 1953 (Box 6)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1950; undated (Box 6)
  - Mission Gallery (Taos, N.M.), 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - Montclair Art Museum, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Morang, Dorothy, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Mosman, Warren T., See Ellerbe and Company.
  - Mozley, Loren, undated (Box 6)
  - Museum of Fine Arts (Boston), 1937; 1957 (Box 6)
  - Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1941-1952 (Box 6)
  - Museum of New Mexico, 1951-1961; undated (Box 6)
  - N (Box 6)
  - Nagler, Fred, 1951 (Box 6)
  - National Academy of Design, 1944-1958; undated (Box 6)
  - [William Rockhill] Nelson Gallery of Art (Kansas City, Mo.), 1952 (Box 6)
  - New Britain Institute Art Museum (New Britain, Conn.), 1953-1957 (Box 6)
  - Nordfeldt, B. J. O. and Emily, 1949-1956; undated (Box 6)
  - O (Box 7)
  - Ogg, Oscar, See Book of the Month Club.
  - Osver, Arthur, 1950-1972 (Box 7)
  - P (Box 7)
  - Paradise, Phil, undated (Box 7)
  - Pearson, Ralph M., 1939; 1950 (Box 7)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1946; 1949,; 1952 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia Water Color Club, 1947-1949 (Box 7)
  - Philbrook Art Center (Tulsa, Okla.), 1947-1954 (Box 7)
  - Phillips, Bert G., 1946; 1949 (Box 7)
  - Princeton Print Club, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
  - Print Club (Philadelphia), 1946-1952 (Box 7)
  - Quick, Marion, undated (Box 7)
  - R (Box 7)
  - Rabow, Alexandre and Rose, 1941-1956 (Box 7)
  - Reed, Doel, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Refregier, Anton, 1953 (Box 7)
  - [Frank K. M.] Rehn, Inc., 1944-1950; undated (Box 7)
  - Roberts, Colette, See Grand Central Art Galleries (New York, N.Y.); Grand Central Moderns (New York, N.Y.).
  - Roberts, George, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
  - Rochester Art Center, 1954-1955 (Box 7)
  - Rood, John and Dorothy, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Rosequist Galleries (Tucson, Ariz.), 1957-1964 (Box 7)
  - Roswell Museum and Art Center (Roswell, N.M.), 1952-1971; undated (Box 7)
  - Rotunda Gallery, City of Paris (San Francisco, Calif.), 1948 (Box 7)
  - Rubenstein, Lewis, 1951; 1964 (Box 7)
  - Rusnell, W. A., 1971 (Box 7)
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1944-1945 (Box 7)
  - Ryder, Worth, 1948 (Box 7)
  - S (Box 7)
  - San Jose State College, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1949-1952 (Box 7)
  - Schneider, Carolyn A., 1953-1962; undated (Box 7)
  - Schooley, Elmer, 1951-1957 (Box 7)
  - Schorre, Charles, 1971; undated (Box 7)
  - Schumann, Sonia, 1963; undated (Box 7)
  - Scripps College, 1950-1953 (Box 7)
  - Seth, Jean, 1971; undated (Box 7)
  - Sheets, Millard and Mary, 1952-1954 (Box 7)
  - Simon, Sidney, undated (Box 7)
  - Slusser, Jean Paul, See University of Michigan Museum of Art.
  - [George Walter Vincent] Smith Art Museum (Springfield, Mass.), 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Society of American Graphic Artists, Inc., See Arms, John Taylor.
  - Spruce, Everett, See University of Texas.
  - Standard Oil Company, 1946 (Box 7)
  - [Edward] Stern and Company Incorporated, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Spiral Press, See Blumenthal, Joseph.
  - Stewart, Albert and Hoppy, 1951; undated (Box 7)
  - Stites, Raymond S. and Margaret, 1948-1964 (Box 7)
  - Stone, Justin, 1963-1964; undated (Box 7)
  - Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, 1952; 1957 (Box 7)
  - T (Box 7)
  - Taos Arts Association, 1963-1971; undated (Box 7)
  - Taos News, 1951-1963; undated (Box 7)
  - Thatcher, Madelaine, 1951-1955; undated (Box 7)
  - Thomas, Kenneth, 1951; undated (Box 7)
  - Tupperware Art Fund, See Fiene, Ernest.
  - U (Box 7)
  - United States Department of State, 1946 (Box 7)
  - United States. Federal Works Agency. Public Buildings Administration, See United States. Public Buildings Administration.
  - United States. Office for Emergency Management, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
  - United States. Office of Civilian Defense, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
  - United States. Post Office, 1938-1941 (Box 7)
    See also United States. Public Buildings Administration; United States. Treasury Department.
  - United States. Public Buildings Administration, 1939-1942; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
    See also United States. Post Office; United States. Treasury Department.
  - United States. Public Buildings Administration. Bulletin Section of Fine Arts, Public Buildings Administration no. 20, 22-24, 1939-1941 (Box 8)
  - United States. Treasury Department, 1935-1939; 1942,; 1945,; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
    See also United States. Post Office; United States. Public Buildings Administration.
  - United States. Treasury Department Art Projects. Bulletin no. 10, 11, 13, 18, 19, 1936-1939 (Box 8)
  - United States. War Department, 1945-1947 (Box 8)
  - University of Hawaii, 1949; 1953 (Box 8)
  - University of Illinois, 1951-1952; undated (Box 8)
  - University of Michigan Museum of Art, 1947-1957 (Box 8)
  - University of Texas, 1962-1964 (Box 8)
    See also Lockwood, Ward.
  - V (Box 8)
  - Valvo, Ninfa, See [M. H.] De Young Memorial Museum.
  - Van Veen, Stuyvesant, 1971-1972; undated (Box 8)
  - W (Box 8)
  - Washington University (St. Louis), 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Watson, Forbes, 1938-1946 (Box 8)
    See also United States. Treasury Department.
  - E. Weyhe, 1935-1943; undated (Box 8)
    See also Zigrosser, Carl.
  - Whitney Museum of American Art (New York, N.Y.), 1940; 1942,; 1951 (Box 8)
  - Whyte, James, 1940-1942 (Box 8)
  - Wichita Art Association, 1947-1948 (Box 8)
  - Winnan, R. Gray, 1970-1971; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Winnan, R. Gray, 1972; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Witte Memorial Museum (San Antonio), 1947; 1953 (Box 9)
  - Woodcut Society, 1941-1942 (Box 9)
  - Year, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Zigrosser, Carl, 1935-1971; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
    See also E. Weyhe.
  - Zigrosser, Laura Canade, See E. Weyhe.
  - Zornes, Milford, See California Water Color Society.
  - Unidentified
    - Incoming, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Outgoing drafts, 2 folders (Box 9)
- Artwork
  - Original
    - Drawings
      - Watercolors, pencil sketches, and page proofs for Cook's children's book, Sammi's Army (Oversize 1)
      - Watercolors for The Reader's Digest, 8 watercolors (Oversize 1)
      - Watercolors for the unpublished Book of the Month Club edition of Jack London's The Call of the Wild, 8 watercolors (Oversize 2)
    - Sketches
      - Self portrait (Box 10)
      - San Antonio frescoes (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Woodcut and lithographic proofs, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Reproductions
    - Illustrations (periodical)
      - Adventure, undated (Box 10)
      - The Atlantic, 1960 (Box 10)
      - Century, 1924 (Box 10)
      - Common Ground, 1941 (Box 10)
      - The Forum, 1925-1933; undated; 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Laughing Horse, 1927 (Box 10)
      - The Nation, 1936; undated (Box 10)
      - New Masses, 1937 (Box 10)
      - New Mexico Quarterly, 1950 (guest artist, H. Cook); 1956 (Box 10)
      - The Reader's Digest, undated (Box 10)
        See also Artwork: Original: Watercolors for The Reader's Digest.
      - Scribner's Magazine, 1937 (Box 10)
      - The Survey, 1922 (Box 10)
      - Survey Graphic, 1922; 1923 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Murals at Mayo Clinic portfolio (Box 10)
      See also Ellerbe and Co.; Mayo Clinic; Writings: Notes: Mayo Clinic project.
    - Miscellaneous (by title) (Box 10)
      - A-Z, untitled, 3 folders (Box 10)
- Writings
  - Articles (by title)
    - A-Z, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Essays
    - "Ernest L. Blumenschein", original draft (Box 11)
  - Inventories of work
    - "Pastel circuit" (Box 11)
    - "Studio sale" (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Reminiscences
  - Speech
    - Untitled "final draft" delivered for Andrew Dasburg retrospective exhibition, Santa Fe, Oct. 1959 (Box 11)
  - Statements and notes on philosophy of art (Box 11)
  - Notes
    - Mayo Clinic Project (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
- Memorabilia
  - Financial (Box 11)
    - Receipts
      - Government projects (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Identification and membership cards, exhibition tickets, etc. (Box 12)
  - Legal
    - Contracts, 1952; undated (Box 12)
  - Photographs (2) student work (Box 12)
  - Printed material
    - Addresses in Honor of American Artists Who Have Decorated Federal Buildings, Apr. 1940 (Box 12)
    - Articles, reviews about, 1925-1963; undated; 7 folders (Box 12)
    - Books (mention of H. Cook)
      - New Mexico Artists, 1952; reprints from New Mexico Quarterly (Box 12)
      - The Book of Fine Prints by Carl Zigrosser, 1948 (Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1923-1965; undated; 9 folders (Box 13)
    - Exhibition announcements, invitations, 1926-1969; undated; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Exhibition catalogs (Cook)
      - Group shows, 1920s-1935; 2 folders of 35 (Box 13)
      - Group shows, 1936-1944; 8 folders of 35 (Box 14)
      - Group shows, 1945-1949; 9 folders of 35 (Box 15)
      - Group shows, 1950-1955; 8 folders of 35 (Box 16)
      - Group shows, 1956-1966; undated; 8 folders of 35 (Box 17)
      - One man shows, 1929-1965; undated (Box 17)
    - Exhibition catalogs (miscellaneous non Cook) (by institution)
      - Brooklyn Museum, 1947; 1951,; 1954 (Box 18)
      - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1945-1947 (Box 18)